<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on CohleM</title>
    <link>https://cohlem.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on CohleM</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 21:57:23 +0545</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cohlem.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Genetic Algorithm for Weights Optimization</title>
      <link>https://cohlem.github.io/posts/using-genetic-algorithm-for-weights-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 21:57:23 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cohlem.github.io/posts/using-genetic-algorithm-for-weights-optimization/</guid>
      <description>BackStory This is a simple fun little project that I did almost a year ago, At that time I used to see a lot of CodeBullet&amp;rsquo;s videos and wanted to learn the gist behind these evolutionary algorithms, and I can&amp;rsquo;t get into my head if I don&amp;rsquo;t do it from scratch so I wanted to implement this project from scratch. At that time, I wanted to document the learning and the implementation process, I even thought of making a youtube video about this topic but could not complete it, at that time, I had made some video animations about this process but could not complete it because I started doing something else and when I can back it was already too much mess and could not complete the video animations, but I&amp;rsquo;ll include the video animations that I had made earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine-tuning LLM vs In-context learning</title>
      <link>https://cohlem.github.io/posts/llmvsincontext/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 20:40:19 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cohlem.github.io/posts/llmvsincontext/</guid>
      <description>This is my experience and experimentation that I did while building a product for the use case of using LLMs for our own data for question answering. If you&amp;rsquo;re doing something similar, this could be of some help.
The most commonly used methods while using LLMs with our own data were typically
Fine-tuning the model with your own data Using Retrieval Augmented Generation (RAG) techniques Fine-tuning the model with your own data This is the initial method and follows the general structure of training a model</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
